Guide to the Stanford Technology Ventures Program, Entrepreneurial Thought Leaders Seminar, Videorecordings SC1209
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Videorecordings, 2001-2014
  - Catmull, Ed, "How to Argue with Steve Jobs", 2014-04-30; 3326; 1 computer file(s) (mov)
    Summary: Catmull, Ed, president and co-founder of Pixar Animation Studios, describes how he would demonstrate patience and persistence when he and the late Steve Jobs did not agree on something. Jobs co-founded Pixar and was its CEO at the time.
  - Catmull, Ed, "Inside the Braintrust", 2014-04-30; 3327; 1 computer file(s) (mov)
    Summary: Catmull, Ed, president of Pixar and Disney Animation Studios, explains the highly effective concept of the "Braintrust," which comprises a group of passionate peers who advise filmmakers during the production process. Key to its success is that the group has no authority, and that absolute candor and trust must be in place, Catmull says.
    Length (seconds): 436
  - Catmull, Ed, "The Hungry Beast and the Ugly Baby", 2014-04-30; 3328; 1 computer file(s) (mov)
    Summary: Catmull, Ed, president of Pixar and Disney Animation Studios, describes how companies often don't spend enough time nurturing and improving an initial idea and quickly produce something lacking because of the pressure to "feed the hungry beast."
    Length (seconds): 128
  - Rottenberg, Linda, "Crazy is a Compliment [Entire Talk]", 2014-05-07; 3329; 1 computer file(s) (mov)
    Length (seconds): 3565
  - Chang, Morris, "An Emphasis on Excellence [Entire Talk]", 2014-04-23; 3330; 1 computer file(s) (mov)
    Length (seconds): 3250
  - Chang, Morris, "Igniting the Foundry Industry", 2014-04-23; 3331; 1 computer file(s) (mov)
    Summary: In conversation with Stanford University President Hennessy, John, TSMC Founding Chairman Morris Chang talks about the rapid increase in fabless semiconductor companies after the creation of his revolutionary chip-making plant. Chang also discusses how TSMC showed competitors in Taiwan how to be a world-class company.
    Length (seconds): 379
  - Chang, Morris, "Finding a Company's Focus", 2014-04-23; 3332; 1 computer file(s) (mov)
    Summary: Responding to a question from Stanford University President Hennessy, John, Morris Chang discusses how playing a leadership role in the semiconductor industry allowed him to see the business opportunity for a manufacturing plant that serves companies without fabrication facilities.
    Length (seconds): 141
  - Chang, Morris, "Japan in the Semiconductor Industry", 2014-04-23; 3333; 1 computer file(s) (mov)
    Summary: Stanford University President Hennessy, John and Morris Chang, founding chairman of TSMC, talk about how Japan fell behind Taiwan, China and Korea in the semiconductor industry. Chang attributes this to the lack of Japanese ôfabless manufacturers,ö chip makers without fabrication facilities.
    Length (seconds): 216
  - Rottenberg, Linda, "Stop Planning, Start Doing", 2014-05-07; 3334; 1 computer file(s) (mov)
    Summary: Linda Rottenberg, co-founder and CEO of Endeavor Global, urges aspiring entrepreneurs to act on their ideas and not get too caught up with elaborate business plans and market research.
    Length (seconds): 93
  - Rottenberg, Linda, "An Unconventional Startup Strategy", 2014-05-07; 3335; 1 computer file(s) (mov)
    Summary: Stalking is an underrated startup strategy, says Linda Rottenberg, co-founder and CEO of Endeavor Global, who illustrates this through the story of Josephine Esther Mentzer, whose relentless salesmanship led to huge success in cosmetics. Mentzer came to be known as Estee Lauder.
    Length (seconds): 131
  - Rottenberg, Linda, "Chaos is the Friend", 2014-05-07; 3336; 1 computer file(s) (mov)
    Summary: Linda Rottenberg, co-founder and CEO of Endeavor Global, discusses how instability in society benefits entrepreneurs more than the status quo. She retells the story of how the French widow behind the brand "Veuve Clicquot" made sure her champagne was poured at key moments during the Napoleonic Wars.
    Length (seconds): 192
  - Rottenberg, Linda, "Tell the Stories", 2014-05-07; 3337; 1 computer file(s) (mov)
    Summary: Linda Rottenberg, co-founder and CEO of Endeavor Global, describes how the success stories of local entrepreneurs in different industries and demographic groups can inspire more entrepreneurship in emerging markets.
    Length (seconds): 107
  - Rottenberg, Linda, "Close Doors and Live Lean", 2014-05-07; 3338; 1 computer file(s) (mov)
    Summary: In conversation with Stanford Prof. Seelig, Tina, Linda Rottenberg warns that keeping all doors and options open can distract one to the point of paralysis. Rottenberg, co-founder and CEO of Endeavor Global, also discussed living ôleanö as a way to free up resources for more risk taking.
    Length (seconds): 121
  - Donaker, Geoff, "The Road to IPO [Entire Talk]", 2014-05-14; 3339; 1 computer file(s) (mov)
    Length (seconds): 3551
  - Donaker, Geoff, "Reasons Not to Sell", 2014-05-14; 3340; 1 computer file(s) (mov)
    Summary: Yelp Chief Operating Officer Geoff Donaker talks about the company's decision to turn down lucrative acquisition offers pre-IPO. While selling would've benefited Yelp's founders and early investors, Donaker says it was unclear what the effect would be for the rest of Yelp's employees and growing user community.
    Length (seconds): 205
  - Donaker, Geoff, "Making the IPO Decision", 2014-05-14; 3341; 1 computer file(s) (mov)
    Summary: Yelp COO Geoff Donaker talks about how the company saw the resignation of its previous chief financial officer as the ideal time to go public. Donaker says an impending IPO made Yelp focus on candidates with previous CFO experience taking a company public.
    Length (seconds): 226
  - Donaker, Geoff, "Going on the Roadshow", 2014-05-14; 3342; 1 computer file(s) (mov)
    Summary: Yelp Chief Operating Officer Geoff Donaker recounts traveling around the country with company leaders to meet with institutional investors prior to the IPO. He explains how the amount of shares bought, and at what price, reflects demand.
    Length (seconds): 422
  - Donaker, Geoff, "Yelp Growth Strategies", 2014-05-14; 3343; 1 computer file(s) (mov)
    Summary: Yelp COO Geoff Donaker describes how the strength of the site lies in all the reviews by everyday people, and how even the small percentage of users who write reviews leads to increased engagement. He also discusses grassroots growth in new cities via recruitment of Yelp "community managers."
    Length (seconds): 243
  - Busque, Leah, "Do Something You Love [Entire Talk]", 2014-05-21; 3345; 1 computer file(s) (mov)
    Length (seconds): 3596
  - Busque, Leah, "Tell Everyone About Your Idea", 2014-05-21; 3346; 1 computer file(s) (mov)
    Summary: Leah Busque, founder and CEO of TaskRabbit, explains the value of sharing a business idea as widely as possible and recounts how doing that over dinner years ago led to a kinship with someone who provided early support and mentorship that proved vital to her startup.
    Length (seconds): 388
  - Busque, Leah, "Growing the Early User Base", 2014-05-21; 3347; 1 computer file(s) (mov)
    Summary: Leah Busque, founder and CEO of TaskRabbit, describes how her business rapidly grew out of a hyper-local beta test: on 600 mothers in her hometown. She also discusses closely tracking customer analytics as a way to guide product development.
    Length (seconds): 109
  - Busque, Leah, "The Early Metrics", 2014-05-21; 3348; 1 computer file(s) (mov)
    Summary: Leah Busque, founder and CEO of TaskRabbit, discusses how performance metrics and customer traction were measured during seed-round fundraising. She says the key then was identifying the right metrics and figuring out how fast goals could be reached.
    Length (seconds): 90
  - Busque, Leah, "Employment Impacts", 2014-05-21; 3349; 1 computer file(s) (mov)
    Summary: Leah Busque, founder and CEO of TaskRabbit, shares statistics on the number of Americans who depend on the site for full-time work and income. She also describes how TaskRabbit empowers individuals to work on their terms and shape their own destiny.
  - Busque, Leah, "Ensuring Fair Prices", 2014-05-21; 3350; 1 computer file(s) (mov)
    Summary: Leah Busque, founder and CEO of TaskRabbit, explains how customers are prohibited from paying errand-runners below minimum wage, and how helpers for hire on the site set their own rate, and more importantly, are empowered to build out their own business.
    Length (seconds): 118